<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kiln:root xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:kiln="http://www.kcl.ac.uk/artshums/depts/ddh/kiln/ns/1.0"
    xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform">
    
    <kiln:parent>
        <xi:include href="works.xml" />
    </kiln:parent>
    
    <kiln:child>
        <kiln:block name="title">
            <kiln:super />
            <xsl:apply-templates mode="title" select="/aggregation/index_metadata" />
        </kiln:block>
        
        <kiln:block name="page-heading">
            <kiln:super />
            <xsl:apply-templates mode="head" select="/aggregation/index_metadata" />
        </kiln:block>

        <kiln:block name="page-header">
            <div class="row">
                <div class="large-12 columns text-center">
                <h1>
                    About
                </h1>
                </div>
            </div>
        </kiln:block>
        
        <kiln:block name="content">
            <div class="row">
                <p>
                The CSAeB is a federated search portal for Byzantine seals, providing access to all collections encoded using the <a href="https://github.com/SigiDoc/Guidelines/wiki">SigiDoc data model</a> through a single unified interface.
                 Rather than merging everything into one large corpus, the portal allows individual collections to remain autonomous while being interoperable through the shared encoding standard.
                To support this approach, the DigiByzSeal team developed an infrastructure based on GitHub repositories:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>A central SigiDoc repository hosts core materials such as schema, templates, and stylesheets. These files are centrally maintained and are not intended to be modified by individual projects.</li>
                    <li>Forkable components, including selected code files and authority lists (standardised names and references), are made available for local adaptation. Projects can propose improvements via pull requests to the central repository.</li>
                    <li>Individual teams (e.g., those in Cologne and Paris) have established their own GitHub organisations, where they manage their EFES-SigiDoc instances and collections of seal editions (in XML format).</li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                Each seal collection is published as XML files, which are integrated into EFES—a web-based viewer for TEI-encoded documents.
                 The federated portal tracks public Git repositories using webhooks. When a new seal is added, the webhook initiates a process that:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Pulls the new XML file from the repository</li>
                    <li>Indexes the file on the EFES-based portal</li>
                    <li>Makes it available in the search interface</li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                This system supports decentralised editing while enabling centralised discovery and search capabilities.
                Importantly, the federated portal does not require projects to use EFES specifically. Even raw XML files hosted publicly on Git platforms can be harvested and indexed.
                The broader aim is to build a collaborative digital infrastructure for sigillography, empowering museums, researchers, and institutions around the world to contribute independently while remaining interconnected.
                </p>
                <hr></hr>
                <h6>Further readings:</h6>
                <p>
                Neuefeind, Claes, Bigalke, Jan, Catalano, Maria Teresa, Drach, Sviatoslav, Efthymoglou, Sofia, Evening, Pia, Filosa, Martina, Malatras, Christos, Schaeben, Marcel,
                 and Sode, Claudia. "Signed, sealed, delivered – digital approaches to Byzantine sigillography." it - Information Technology, 2024. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1515/itit-2023-0030">https://doi.org/10.1515/itit-2023-0030</a>
                </p>
                <p>
                Sopracasa, Alessio, Bigalke, Jan, Buchs, Numa, and Meziridou, Sima. 2024. “Creating a Sigillographic Search Engine for Byzantium: Preliminary Results.” 
                In Digital Approaches to Medieval Sigillography, ed. Martina Filosa, Claes Neuefeind, and Claudia Sode, special collection. Digital Medievalist 17(1): 1–32. <a href="https://doi.org/10.16995/dm.15235">https://doi.org/10.16995/dm.15235</a>
                </p>
            </div>
        </kiln:block>
    </kiln:child>
    
</kiln:root>
